Thank you.
And thank you for having me in this beautiful office.
It's super cool.
Yeah, so...
Synth is essentially a
probabilistic intelligence layer for asset prices.
So we focus very much on
getting people to forecast price path distributions
versus
trying to forecast just individual prices in the future.
Which is pretty common for most kind of like
finance competitions, trading competitions.
A lot of them are focused on like point predictions
some point in the future
and we're focused on distributions.
So you know you've really got to try and
forecast where the price will go and how it will go there.
The competition is based on Bittensor as a subnet.
Competitors
submit a thousand paths or Monte Carlo simulations.
Every hour on a continuous basis and are scored on
how accurate their distributions are to the actual price.
So it's live, it's ongoing.
Super excited to expand
the different people that can access the competition
by working with Crunch.
My co-founder Sam and I have spent a lot of time
like building out different trading systems,
especially in crypto decentralized finance.
We've also competed in competitions in the past like
Numerai competition.
And we really like the idea that, you know, you can
you can crowdsource intelligence.
And for us
around a year ago,
we started to think about what would agents and LLMs
that are going to be like the
primary users of markets in the future
what do they need?
And they already have access to like
all the historical data they could want.
And they're very good at answering questions about historical data.
But LLMs agents aren't very good at answering questions
about the future
so can you create this intelligence layer
that they can tap into to answer questions
better about the future?
And for this you want to have...
get an open competition or you want to have a lot of competitors
who can kind of create a really robust data layer
intelligence layer
that people can tap into.
For that you need to have a very transparent scoring mechanism.
You need to make sure it's fair
and you need to make sure the participants are well paid.
We think we've achieved a lot of those things with Synth
and we now have a very competitive environment.
With high reward
like roughly around a hundred thousand dollars per month in rewards
going out to participants.
Which is cool.
And we have really strong data sets that agents can tap into.
But we've also seen like
Trading firms.
Different traders,
people who do risk management also tapping into this data.
You can apply it to options markets, prediction markets.
Yeah it's cool.
Yeah, so we use continuous rank probability scoring system.
So you're continuously ranked on
how close your distributions are to the actual price movement.
And this rewards people who are confident
and like very confident in their distribution and are correct.
It punishes people who are confident and incorrect.
And people who are vague,
the more vague you are
the more likely you are to have a very mediocre score.
And the subnet is weighted to people who have
accurate predictions.
Accurate forecasts of distributions.
They receive the most rewards.
So yeah...
It's quite hard to cheat.
There's also like a negative cost.
So if you try and do things like register lots of participants,
then
it's very unlikely that will be successful
some will get deregistered and there's a cost to that.
We found that like the scoring mechanism has
kind of evolved over time.
It's got a lot more robust.
It's in a great position right now.
The optimal strategy is to try to be as accurate as possible
from the very beginning and just improve your model over time
and it's very likely you're going to do well.
I think that's what we love about working with Crunch is that
it's making the subnet more accessible,
making the competition much more accessible.
And we're discussing as well earlier
there's so many more tools available now.
And you don't have to be an expert in finance by any means
to enter the competition, right?
Especially through Crunch.
Just have skills from different industries.
And this is a great place to learn about
time series, Monte Carlo simulations and modeling.
So yeah, it's very exciting.
Yeah.
Yeah, absolutely.
So firstly,
like it is very competitive, like because the prices are significant.
That's roughly like
$80,000 to $100,000 per month in rewards
going out to participants. So yeah.
The prizes are significant.
So yeah, there is a lot of competition.
Real players are coming in.
Some of them have also worked at, you know.
Various places where they've got some experience with this.
The quality of the data over the last few months
has improved like a lot.
We ran an experiment on Polymarket
where we're trading some binary up/down, yes/no
up/down markets.
We had an account, I think it started around $3,000
turned into $60,000 to $70,000.
Recently we've seen some interesting behavior on the market.
On Polymarket.
So we created a dashboard, we created some tools
So people can...
you know, see if there's any discrepancies between
Synth's probabilistic forecasts and
and the Polymarket prices on certain markets
which can help them with their own trading.
Yeah-yeah, we saw last week around a week ago.
Someone was moving the price of BTC to try and win markets.
They were also moving the price of XRP.
Just like 10-20 seconds before the end of the market.
We were seeing a lot of discrepancy, you know.
This potentially caused a lot of like automated systems
that didn't have like this level of data to lose money.
We think that like probabilistic forecasts
that they can be useful for a huge amount of
things across trading, across risk management.
You can integrate this data into like
automated trading systems, options markets.
There's a lot of applications.
But as you said,
the key is to have a great competition,
so really great, strong robust data comes out of it.
We've seen a lot of demand for crypto data.
But we've added equities
and we think that there's going to be a huge amount of demand
for like 24/7 data across equities
as we see like stock exchanges.
They're all moving to become 24/5.
Exactly. Yeah.
So 24 hour trading is coming.
No sleep in 2026.
Yeah, we didn't have it in 2025.
Yeah, too long.
Exactly.
So like, there's gonna be this big regime shift
where equities come onchain.
I think probabilistic data is going to become a lot more important.
And we're seeing a lot of demand for this.
People using the data within like risk management systems
within trading systems.
I also think that the way that we have like this new
kind of group of pro retail traders emerging
so people who have started using different tools
like different technologies to start trading
so maybe it's building their own algorithms or
maybe they're using Claude to
create more complex trading strategies than they used to have.
Maybe they're integrating different data sets
into their trading strategies.
I think this trend is going to continue over the coming year.
There'll be more demand for probabilistic data for sure.
I think it's creating like this perfect storm.
So yeah, we're in a good position, but no sleep in 2026.
Good question.
In total, we have 9 assets.
So we may add more in the future.
Our goal is to create this broad intelligence layer.
We definitely will add some more assets.
kind of based on demand.
We're seeing silver is in demand right now.
It's had great performance recently,
so potentially adding in silver models in the future.
We might add in more equities.
We're pretty open to responding to demand, but right now
we've just added in some equity.
So we'll make sure that performance is good there.
Then we'll see in the near future.
The key thing is to really think about:
this is a volatility modeling competition.
Volatility is based on multiple factors,
but right now
Volatility is very much based on different news events.
So reacting to those news events
or having ways to bring that data into your model is very important.
Yeah, exactly.
News is moving the market significantly.
I think it's key to like try and bring in different news feeds,
social media data into your models that can really help performance.
Pyth is the price data and the oracle we use.
It's very robust. They have a great system.
But for your modeling
you can explore different data sets, right?
As many different data sets as possible.
You mentioned that's also now possible.
Solana?
And SOL.
Amazing.
Absolutely.
Awesome.
Let's do it.
Super excited.
Thank you so much.